<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jeremy Buchmann - beer</title><link href="http://jeremybuchmann.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jeremybuchmann.com/feeds/beer.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jeremybuchmann.com/</id><updated>2017-05-07T11:49:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Beer and The Beauty of Tables</title><link href="http://jeremybuchmann.com/beer-tables.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-07T11:49:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-07T11:49:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jeremy Buchmann</name></author><id>tag:jeremybuchmann.com,2017-05-07:/beer-tables.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My grandfather was a machinist. He started out in the 1930s working on
airplane engines and later worked as a tool and die maker, moldmaker, and
millwright into the 1980's. Even in retirement, he took odd jobs fixing
tractors and rebuilding various machine parts. Eventually, the time came
for him …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My grandfather was a machinist. He started out in the 1930s working on
airplane engines and later worked as a tool and die maker, moldmaker, and
millwright into the 1980's. Even in retirement, he took odd jobs fixing
tractors and rebuilding various machine parts. Eventually, the time came
for him to get rid of a lot of his old tools, and he gave me his old tool
chest that he had purchased and been using since the 30s. In the
middle of this chest is an odd-looking vertical drawer that would look
out of place in any modern tool chest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="tool chest" src="http://jeremybuchmann.com/images/tool-chest.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(this is not my chest, but it's very similar)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This strange vertical drawer was designed (I believe) to hold a book
called simply
&lt;a href="http://new.industrialpress.com/resources/history"&gt;"Machinery's Handbook"&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="machinery's handbook" src="http://jeremybuchmann.com/images/machinerys-handbook.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First
published in 1914, Machinery's Handbook is a compendium of information
for machinists such as trigonometry, thread sizes, cutting speeds, feed
speeds, metal alloys, and more. Even a casual perusal of this book will
show you that much of this information is delivered in tables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="machining tables" src="http://jeremybuchmann.com/images/machining-tables.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beauty of printed tables is their simplicity of use; find the
column, find the row, find the value. You don't need to train someone
how to use them, they don't need batteries, and you can copy them, tape
them on things, and make notes in the margins. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analog nature of "in-between" values makes tables seem out-of-place
in a world of screens with 20 digits of resolution, but this provides a cogent
reminder that most of those digits are not important. Billions of
smooth-running, high-performance machines were built from data on printed
tables with four digits of resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how does all this relate to beer? In brewing, there are a lot of formulas for 
calculations such as mash pH, water chemistry, original gravity, IBUs, and 
hydrometer correction. Many of these formulas are complex and better handled by software such as Beersmith 
or online calculators, but for some cases, it's hard to beat the simplicity of printed tables. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, a hydrometer correction is a simple two-variable lookup. If you
know the temperature of the wort sample and it's hydrometer reading, you can
lookup the corrected value in a table. After some online research, I wrote a
quick-and-dirty script to generate hydrometer corrections for various gravity
readings at various temperatures. Here is the table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://jeremybuchmann.com/pdfs/HydrometerTemperatureCorrection68F.pdf"&gt;Hydrometer Temperature Correction Table (68F)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I can't garantee that it's correct, but I use it :-)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="beer"></category></entry></feed>