<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jeremy Buchmann - misc</title><link href="http://jeremybuchmann.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jeremybuchmann.com/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jeremybuchmann.com/</id><updated>2018-09-17T19:08:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>The Best Line in Spaceballs</title><link href="http://jeremybuchmann.com/the-best-line-in-spaceballs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-17T19:08:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-17T19:08:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jeremy Buchmann</name></author><id>tag:jeremybuchmann.com,2018-09-17:/the-best-line-in-spaceballs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0094012/"&gt;Spaceballs&lt;/a&gt; was one of my favorite movies as a kid. Its juvenile, 4th-wall breaking humor was endlessly entertaining to a 10 year-old me. My friend and I even had the final duel scene between Dark Helmet and Lone Starr memorized so well that we would act it out at the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0094012/"&gt;Spaceballs&lt;/a&gt; was one of my favorite movies as a kid. Its juvenile, 4th-wall breaking humor was endlessly entertaining to a 10 year-old me. My friend and I even had the final duel scene between Dark Helmet and Lone Starr memorized so well that we would act it out at the beginning of PE class when the instructors were trying to get all us kids lined up for calisthenics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently watched the movie again for some nostalgic laughs. Although there are a few bits that haven't aged well, I think that overall, the movie holds up. But there was one joke toward the end that really jumped out at me as being very timely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EfkNvOOiZ_8?start=139" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fuck! Even in the future nothing works!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I'm just becoming an old man, but that sums up how I feel about &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/internetofshit"&gt;a lot of things&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Hack4Reno Recap</title><link href="http://jeremybuchmann.com/hack4reno-recap.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-11-09T13:02:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-11-09T13:02:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jeremy Buchmann</name></author><id>tag:jeremybuchmann.com,2015-11-09:/hack4reno-recap.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="badge" src="http://jeremybuchmann.com/images/hack-for-reno-badge.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://hack4reno.com/"&gt;Hack4Reno Summit&lt;/a&gt; was devised as a data and
project sharing event to be used as a thought-builder for the annual
Hack4Reno Hackathon in the spring. Hack4Reno happened last Saturday;
here's my recap:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashleyzhand"&gt;Ashley Hand&lt;/a&gt; (LA Civic
Innovator and Architect) gave the keynote and pointed to some
interesting facts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="badge" src="http://jeremybuchmann.com/images/hack-for-reno-badge.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://hack4reno.com/"&gt;Hack4Reno Summit&lt;/a&gt; was devised as a data and
project sharing event to be used as a thought-builder for the annual
Hack4Reno Hackathon in the spring. Hack4Reno happened last Saturday;
here's my recap:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashleyzhand"&gt;Ashley Hand&lt;/a&gt; (LA Civic
Innovator and Architect) gave the keynote and pointed to some
interesting facts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most people (72%) trust local government (as opposed to federal).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government communication is often the problem, not the services
    themselves. Example: surveyed opinion of snowplow service in some
    city (Cleveland?) went up after the city implemented a real-time
    snowplow location and plowing schedule online, even though the
    plowing service didn’t change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government doesn’t always communicate within itself. Example: a
    group of state employees were given the task to find a data set from
    another department that none of them worked in within 10 minutes.
    They tried Googling, calling co-workers, and other methods, but none
    of them got the data in time. The presenter got the data in 30
    seconds from a data portal that none of the participants knew
    existed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are benefits to testing “smarter city” ideas in a “living lab”
    environment before rolling them out city-wide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrew-clinger-53857569"&gt;Andrew Clinger&lt;/a&gt;
(Reno City Manager) showed off the new city data portal which runs on
&lt;a href="https://www.socrata.com/"&gt;Socrata&lt;/a&gt;. It’s nice, but terribly expensive
(almost \$100k…not sure if that’s once or per year).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/will-kurt-2591a155"&gt;Will Kurt&lt;/a&gt; (Data
Scientist) gave an eye-opening talk on mathematical Expectation vs.
Variance as it relates to evaluating risk and making predictions based
on data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/adamon"&gt;Anjeanette Damon&lt;/a&gt; (reporter for
RGJ) discussed data-driven and data-enabled journalism. Example: using
real-estate data to discover short-sale scams perpetrated by
unscrupulous real estate agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joechavez"&gt;Joe Chavez&lt;/a&gt; (Software Engineer)
talked about the nuts and bolts of hackathons, both public and
intra-organization, and how to participate in one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jessicacarsten"&gt;Jessica Carsten&lt;/a&gt; from
Socrata gave a great talk on data portals. Main points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data is the tool, not the end result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal users may/should be the primary end users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start with what you’ve got.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t make public data 2nd class; eat your own dog food.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automate publishing, otherwise you are just contributing to future
    bit rot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push data to existing portals where people already go, i.e. real
    estate data to Zillow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/keithanderson"&gt;Keith Anderson&lt;/a&gt; (President
of Trinity Applied Internet) showed how to create APIs from static data
(like a table on a web page) with &lt;a href="https://www.kimonolabs.com/"&gt;Kimono&lt;/a&gt;
which was really, really awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim Robinson discussed regional planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashleynoelhennefer"&gt;Ashley Hennefer&lt;/a&gt;
(Writer &amp;amp; Researcher) talked about how to participate in hackathons
without being a programmer. Designers, testers, writers, presenters and
various subject-matter experts as also needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lynnecbarker"&gt;Lynne Barker&lt;/a&gt; (Sustainability
Manager at City of Reno) discussed tools such as
&lt;a href="http://www2.mysidewalk.com/"&gt;mysidewalk&lt;/a&gt; for evaluating sustainability
needs and pointed out that manual data gathering is expensive and should
be automated where possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alicia-barber-26a96125"&gt;Alicia Barber&lt;/a&gt;
(Historian) discussed the presentation of historical data using mobile
apps which allow self-guided tours with photos, oral histories, and
text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew Bertman from &lt;a href="http://filament.com/"&gt;Filament&lt;/a&gt; discussed his
company’s wireless IoT products which are aiming for as much as 10 miles
of line-of-sight range with 3-5 years of battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kelseymccutcheon"&gt;Kelsey Fitzgerald&lt;/a&gt;
(Science Writer) discussed the challenges and benefits of crowdsourcing
data, specifically, a species survey of the Truckee River. The gist was
that crowdsourcing is best for creating a conversation around data, and
may be the only way to obtain data if you have no money. In terms of
obtaining the data, it is slow, difficult to keep people motivated, and
can lead to erroneous data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/colinmrobertson"&gt;Colin Robertson&lt;/a&gt; (Curator)
discussed the intersections of art and data and data-inspired artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://projectbaseline.org/"&gt;Project Baseline&lt;/a&gt; discussed their efforts
to use SCUBA divers as citizen scientists for gathering data on change
in aquatic environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some students from UNR presented GIS data from the
&lt;a href="http://renotracks.nevadabike.org/"&gt;RenoTracks&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry></feed>